CURRICULUMVITAE

JobProfile-CivilEngineer

RAJAT SINGH

Vill-Bhikhampur

Post-Aspurdeosara

Distt-Pratapgarh(U.P)

Pincode-230124

Mahila 2014/12472000 265101856

Mobile no:+919113472900 , 9651018562 EmailID-singhrajat2357@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I could gain the opportunity to learn more about highway & railway engineering construction from the highly experienced professionals. I have also worked under tough and challenging conditions. I steel feel there is lot more to learn and I hope my endeavor steamed organization, if an opportunity is given to serve for you. Ability to do honest & intelligent hard work, to learn new concepts, to work in a team.

PROFILE SUMMARY:

I having More than 3 years of experience in the field of Highway. I was deeply involved in the various activities of the Quality Control of the materials and materials produced by the different plants e.g. Concrete bathing plant, hot mix plant and WMM plant. I am having experience in various Mix Designs of Flexible and Concrete pavement as well as structural concrete. During my working period, I am also responsible for the materials produced by the Crusher with the proper gradation and used materials in the various Job mix Formula. I was responsible for supervising all the testes and to maintain all the Laboratory records for internal and client's audit. I am well conversant with IS, BS codes & MORTH specification .

Educational Qualification

Examination	Year of passing	Board	Percentage(%)
High school	2011	U.P. Board Allahabad	60
Intermediate	2013	U.P. Board Allahabad	76

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION

Examination	Year of passing	University	Percentage
Diploma in Civil Engineering	2018	Shobhit University Gangoh Saharanpur.	79

Qualification:

O Computer knowledge – MS Word & MS Excel & AutoCAD

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Period : From oct 2020 to till date

Organization : DILIP BUILDCON LTD Position : Assistant Engineer

Consultant : Voyants Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Client : NATIONAL HIGHWAY AUTHORITY OF INDIA (NHAI)

Project : Construction and upgradation of NH-131A from KM 34.600 (design ch:6.000) near narenpur

to Km 79.970(design ch: 53.000) near purnea to 4 lane standard from Km 79.970 (design ch:

53.000)to Km 82.000(design ch: 55.000) near purnea to 2 lane with paved shoulders

standard in the state of bihar on Hybrid annuity Mode.

Period: From Nov 2019 to Sep 2020

Organization : Vijay Construction India Pvt. Ltd.

Position. : junior Engineer

Consultant . : SMEC India Pvt. Ltd.

Client : Public Work Department, Government of Uttar Pradesh.

Project : Upgradation and Maintenance of MDR No 25E Kaptanganj-Hata Gauribazar-Barhaj Road

Ch. 0.000 to 61.150 (Section from Ch. 0.000 to 57.400 and Bypass Km 3.750) a . .

. Kaptanganj Naurangiya ODR No 24 (Section from Ch. 0.000 to 24.040) in District.

. Kushinagar Uttar Pradesh.

Period: From Sep 2018 to Oct 2019

Organization : Anmol Associate

Position. : junior Engineer

Consultant : VKS INDIA Pvt . Ltd.

Client. : Public Work Department , Government of Uttar Pradesh.

Project: Rehabilitation and Up-gradation of NH-730 From Km.537.000 to Km.

564.750 (Kaptanganj to Padrauna) to Two lane with paved shoulders (Rural Area) & four lane Divided. Carriageway with Service Road (Urban area) under EPC Mode in the state of

uttar pradesh

WORK EXPERIENCE

Working in the field of Highway Construction, Road work and laboratory as a Jr. Engineer – Q.C.Supervisor of laying of DBM BC SDBC WMM, GSB, Sub-Grade and Embankment layers. Conducted quality control tests on Embankment, Sub-Grade, WMM, GSB and Bituminous layers as per specifications of MORT&H, IS, BS, ASTM and AASTHO as required and maintaining all records and monitoring the work. The tests details are given below.

- > **SOIL TESTS**: Borrow area selection and sampling, Grain size Analysis of Soil, Liquid Limit and Plastic Limit, Modified Proctor by IS, CBR value, Free Swell Index, Specific Gravity and Field Dry Density by Sand Replacement Method.
- ➤ **GSB/WMM TESTS**: Gradation, Liquid Limit and Plastic Limit, Proctor Test, CBR, Flakiness & Elongation, Aggregate Impact Value, Water Absorption and Specific Gravity, Sand Equivalent Value, Ten Percent Fines Value for GSB, and Field Dry Density by Sand Replacement method.
- CONCRETE TEST: Compressive strength test, Flexural strength test, slump test,
- **DBM/BC TESTS**: Gradation, Marshal & Flow test, Extraction test, Flakiness & Elongation, Aggregate Impact Value, Water Absorption and Specific Gravity, Sand Equivalent Value and Cone Density by core cutting method.
- AGGREGATE TEST: Sieve analysis, Aggregate Impact Value, Flakiness & Elongation index, Water absorption & Specific gravity and Soundness of stone as per Indian Standards and MORT&H Specifications.
- **CEMENT TEST :** Fineness (Dry sieve analysis) test, Consistency test, Initial & Final setting time, Soundness (by Lee chateliter method), Compressive strength at 03 days, 07 days and 28 days.
- ➤ **RIGID PAVEMENT**: DLC/PQC laying and all required frequency testing.
- > BITUMEN TESTS: Penetration, Softening point, Flash & Fire Point, Viscosity, Ductility and Specific Gravity test.

JOB RESPONSIBILITY:

- Sampling & testing of Borrow area and Site Soil samples.
- Documentation like borrow area, Quantity, RFI, details of tests, weather register and Bar chart.
- Quality control test to maintain frequency as per satisfaction.
- Responsible for the production of Concrete from Batching Plant.
- Calibration of Lab Equipments report preparation.
- Calibration of WMM plant, Hot Mix plant and Concrete Batching Plant.
- Deals with consultant as regards to execution of work.
- > Discuss with management regarding planning and progress of concern work.
- ➤ Identify defects for rectification at various stages of construction.
- > Maintaining well grading of Coarse aggregate as per approved Mix Design for concrete.
- > Inspects Works carried out by the Sub-Contractor for compliance of agreed methodology.
- Design work: bituminous work (BM, DBM, SDBC & BC), GSB, WMM, Filter Media and Concrete.

.Personal Details

Father's Name : Mr. Sandeep Singh
Date of birth : 20 August 1996

Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian

Language Known : English, Hindi

CERTIFICATION.

I, undersigned certify that to the best of my knowledge and belief the curriculum vitae correctly describes my qualification my experience and myself .

(Rajat Singh)